eflow.ie 2017-02-25

# Privacy & Cookies

* * *

#### 1\. General

1.1 This eFlow website is operated by Sanef ITS Operations Ireland Limited ("emovis operations Ireland") on behalf of Transport Infrastructure Ireland ("TII"). emovis operations Ireland and the TII fully respects your right to privacy, and will not collect any personal information about you on this website without your clear knowledge and permission. Any personal information which you volunteer to us will be treated strictly in accordance with the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003.

1.2 Please read the terms of this privacy statement carefully, as by visiting this website you will be deemed to have accepted the terms of this privacy statement.

#### 2\. Collection and use of personal information

2.1 We will collect no personally identifying information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide that information to us. The information we collect depends on what you do when visiting our site.

2.2 If you visit our site to browse, read or download we automatically collect and store your IP address, browser type and length of user sessions. We use this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors, to learn about the number of visitors to our site and the type of technology our visitors use. We do not track or record information about individuals on their visits. We may compile and report aggregate statistics about our users in terms of numbers, traffic patterns and related site information. Any such statistics will not include any personally identifying information.

2.3 You may choose to provide us with personal data (e.g. name, email and postal address) in correspondence to one of the addresses listed on our website. We use these details solely for the purpose of dealing with your query.

2.4 If you open an account or pay a toll on our website, we ask you to provide us with, amongst other things, your name, email address, contact telephone number, vehicle registration number and credit card, debit card or direct debit details. We use this data for the purposes of processing your toll payment and/or managing your tag account. We do not collect any more personal data than is necessary to fulfil these purposes.

#### 3\. Disclosure of Personal Data

3.1 We may disclose your personal data to our agents, contractors and service providers to the extent reasonably required for the purposes described above.

3.2 We may also share information about the way you conduct your Tag account with credit reference agencies.

#### 4\. Cookies

4.1 This website uses cookies, so a cookie may be placed in your internet browser. Cookies are small text files which provide us with information about how often someone visits our site, and what he/she does during those visits. Cookies do not themselves contain any personally identifying information but if you provide information to us, it may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.

4.2 If you do not want your browser to accept cookies, you can turn off the cookie acceptance option in your browser settings. Disabling cookie support may prevent this website from functioning properly and you may not be able to utilise fully all of its features and information.

For more information about the way this website uses cookies click here.

#### 5\. Security

5.1 For site security purposes and to ensure that this website remains available to all users, our computer system employs software programs to monitor network traffic in order to identify unauthorised attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage. Unauthorised attempts to upload information or change information on our website are strictly prohibited and may be punishable by law.

5.2 Your personal data which you provide to us will be held on secure servers hosted by emovis operations Ireland. The nature of the internet is such that we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us online. However, we take all reasonable steps (including appropriate technical and organisational security measures) to protect your personal data.

#### 6\. Changes to this Privacy Statement

6.1 From time to time we may decide to change our privacy statement, but any changes will be posted on this page to keep you up to date with how we collect, use and disclose information. If at any time we decide to use personal data in a manner significantly different from that stated in this privacy statement, or otherwise disclosed to you at the time it was collected, we will notify you, and you will have the choice as to whether or not we use your information in the new manner.

#### 7\. Right of Access and Deletion of Data

7.1 You have the right, subject to certain exemptions, to obtain a copy of any personal data we hold about you and to correct any inaccuracies in such data. You also have the right, subject to certain conditions, to request the deletion of any personal data we hold about you. If you wish to avail of any of these rights, please write to us at: eFlow, Cape House, Westend Office Park, Dublin 15, marked for the attention of the "Data Protection Officer". Your request will be dealt with as soon as possible and will not take more than 40 days to process.

## Cookie Policy

#### 1\. Purpose

The purpose of this policy is to provide visitors to the eFlow website with a clear understanding of how our website uses cookies and to explain how cookies can be managed by visitors to our site.

#### 2\. Scope

This policy is applicable to [eflow.ie](http://www.eflow.ie/)

#### 3\. Introduction

A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your computer by your web browser during your interaction with various websites. Cookies on the eFlow website consist of anonymous information about the user and are used by our website for various reasons including;

  * to track a user’s session login so that each user can navigate securely and undisrupted across different web pages of our website;
  * to balance the amount of incoming network traffic accessing services from eFlow web servers;
  * to provide a reliable mechanism for our website to remember the state of the website or activity the user had taken in the past. This can include what selections and/or what pages were visited by the user in the past.

Some cookies on our website are “strictly” necessary for the services of the website to function whilst some are “not strictly” necessary but are required to provide a better customer experience and/or provide us with information for the purposes of future enhancement of the site. Other “third party” cookies are used for providing additional tools and gadgets on the site.

#### 4.0 Cookie Types 

Session cookies used for maintaining a users login credentials throughout a web session and/or for load-balancing are strictly necessary on our website in order for the site to function and perform at an acceptable service level. These cookies do not capture nor do they retain any personal information, as follows:

Maintaining User Credentials |  We use session cookies to enable you to carry out some essential functions on our website, such as maintaining login details for each session as you navigate through various pages and avail of various services on our site such as; registering for an account, making a payment and more. 

Session cookies also improve the performance of the website by minimising the need to repeatedly transfer information across the internet whilst providing a website service.   
  
---|---  
Load Balancing | We use a session cookie for load-balancing purposes to analyse and distribute incoming network traffic across our web servers. This balancing is necessary for providing an acceptable level of performance from our website services.  
  
Session cookies are not permanently stored on your device and expire when you terminate your browser session.

**4.2 Cookies That Are Not Strictly Necessary**

Persistent Cookies are used to collect statistical information from users on our website and to enhance customer experience on our site. These cookies are used by us to enhance our customers experience during their use of our site and to continuously improve our site, as follows:

Persistent cookies may reside on your device for a period of time but do not collect any personal information from any user. 

Google Analytics | We use an analytics service from Google to enable us to recognise repeat visitors to our websites. By  matching an anonymous, randomly generated identifier, we are able to record specific browsing information such as the source of your path to our site, the pages you have viewed, what options you  have selected, and the path you have taken to navigate your way around our site. Having this information allows us to continually improve our sites.  
---|---  
Repeat Visitor Identification | We use persistent cookies to identify repeat visitors to our reward card site. This cookie enhances user experience by preventing the repeated introduction splash-screen for repeat users of the service.  
  
#### 4.3 Third-Party Cookies

We provide some additional features on our website in the form of tools and gadgets that we believe may be of interest to some of our customers, as follows:

Tools and Gadgets | To provide extra functionality for our users, we have in place some tools and gadgets on our websites. Tools such as RSS feeds are in place to show feeds from popular broadcasters which we feel may be of benefit to our users (e.g. Irish Times, weather forecasts etc.). Other tools provide quick links to popular websites (e.g. Amazon.com).  
---|---  
  
Third-Party cookies are not controlled by us and we cannot access how they work. We advise you to check with these third-party organisations for more information about the control of these cookies.

Please also note that our website provides links to some of our business partners and to other organisations such as charities that we may have worked with throughout the year. By clicking on any of these links you may be brought to the website of that particular organisation. Each of these organisations may set their own cookies on your web browser which we have no control over.

## 5\. Controlling Cookies

By using our website you agree that we can place cookies that are both strictly necessary and those that are not strictly necessary on your device.

If you wish to restrict or block the web browser cookies set on your device, you can do this through your web browser settings. The “Help” function within each browser explains how to change these settings, as follows:   

**_Microsoft Internet Explorer_**

**_Google Chrome_**

****_Firefox_****

**_Safari_**

For more comprehensive information on how to manage cookies on a wide range of browser types, including details on how to block cookies from your device please visit [http://aboutcookies.org](http://aboutcookies.org/)

Please note that blocking cookies may restrict many of the functions and services the website has to offer. If you share the use of a device your cookie settings will affect all users of that device.
